Hello friend, ICICI LB General Insurance
Company has declared its quarter 4 results.
So we will analyze that
in this video.  In the meeting
held today, the company has declared a dividend of ₹7.
So let's go ahead and the
value on your screen is
in lax.  But while discussing it with you, I will
convert it into crores.  Let's start with
net premium earned.  So the
net premium earned by the company in the March quarter was Rs
5225 crore.  Whereas in the March quarter of last year it was Rs
4368 crore.  That means
we are seeing a jump of 20% in net premium earnings on year-on-year basis.
Whereas
in the December quarter, net premium earned was Rs 545 crore.  That
means
we are seeing a jump of 4% on quarter on quarter basis also.  The
market estimate was Rs
550 crore.  This means that
net premium earnings are
seeing an increase as per market expectations.  If
we look at the total income in the March quarter, the
total income for the March quarter was Rs
5851 crore.  Last year, it was Rs
5165 crore in the March quarter and Rs 5882 crore in the December quarter.  That means,
if we
look here, we are seeing a jump of 13% on year on year basis.
But on a
quarter-on-quarter basis, we are seeing a fall of 1%
in total income.
Now let us see how the total expenses of the company have been.
So the total expenses in the March quarter were Rs
5435 crore.  And last year
in the March quarter it was worth Rs
464 crore.  Whereas
in the December quarter the
total expenses were Rs 5197 crore.
If we look at the net profit of the company, it has a
net profit of Rs 59 crore in the March quarter.
Whereas last year
in the March quarter it was Rs 59 crore.  That means,
if we look at it on year on year basis,
we are seeing an increase of 2% in net profit.  The
net profit in the December quarter was Rs
724 crore.  That means
we are seeing a fall of 30% in net profit on quarter on quarter basis.  The
market estimate of net
profit was Rs 580 crore.  That means, if we
look here, we are seeing a net profit that is weaker than expected.
If we
look at the company's solvency ratio, which should be a
minimum of 1.5 i.e. above 150%,
it is 269%, whereas last year it was
262% in the March quarter and
236% in December.  If
we look at the combined ratio, it was 102.5% in the March quarter,
102.3% in last March and
102.7% in December, that is, if we look at it on quarter on
quarter basis and year on year basis,
we are seeing almost similar combined ratio.
Now let's look at basic EPS.
So the basic EPS was ₹1.29 in the March quarter
and last year it was ₹1.55 in March and
₹14.63 in December.  That is,
if we compare with March last year, then almost
similar EPS i.e. earnings per share is being
seen.  But there is a
decline in EPS on quarter on quarter basis.
If we look at the results, we can
see slightly negative sides.
Because we are seeing an increase in the net premium earn.
But net profit is declining on quarter on
quarter basis and year on year basis.
And
we are seeing net profit that is weaker than what the market had estimated.
If we look at the performance of the stock in the last 3 months, then a
fall of 4% is being seen in the stock in the last 3 months.
Please let us know how you liked the result
by commenting and also like the video and
subscribe to the channel.  Thank
you.